NICHOLAS DeCHANT

Bellevue, Washington · (425) 922-1585 · dchant@uw.edu · in/NicholasDeChant · nickdec.github.io

A skilled data analytics and customer focused professional with 2.5+ years of proven analytics experience at PACCAR Parts division. Areas of expertise include handling multiple projects and priorities, interpreting and communicating technical issues, and reporting findings with Tableau to present insight for decision making and areas of improvement.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Operations Support Analyst, PACCAR Parts

May 2023 – Current

- Support North American Distribution Centers (PDC's) and Operations team with ad-hoc data requests and analytics projects. Use Snowflake to query multiple sources to create reports and prepare data.
- Develop Live real-time Tableau dashboards for PDC's to improve efficiency and business processes.

 -Tune SQL queries for performance within Tableau to display real-time ASI data in Tableau.
 - -Translate Microsoft Access databases into Tableau products for all PDC's to use and ensure reliability.
- Manage Operations Tableau reports on Tableau Server and Poppulo Digital Signage inside warehouses. Improve or modify existing dashboards on devices for new data or custom metrics.
- Assist Operations Analytics Manager with data projects and collaborate to improve processes.
 - -Designed Split Outbound Lines Tableau to track employees who are splitting lines for Outbound.
 - -Developed e-Packing integration tracking Tableau to manage dealers on Electronic Packing Slips.
- Compile monthly Performance Rating Goals and Performance (PPR) scorecard for all PDC's globally.

Sr. Retail Promotions Analyst, PACCAR Parts

March 2021 – May 2023

- Developed advanced data analytics tools for reporting customer and dealer loyalty metrics including:
 - YTD/PYTD loyalty performance Tableau's for Membership Signups and Redemption Summaries (5000+ views).
 - Loyalty Offer Recommendation report to suggest creation of new Parts coupons for Product Marketing.
- Provided expertise on the loyalty program and presented information to internal and external clients.
 - Conducted monthly WebEx seminars for Loyalty program updates to Kenworth and Peterbilt dealers.
 - Provided classroom trainings for Parts/Sales Managers on how to use the loyalty program and increase sales.
- Analyzed and solved technical business and customer issues within the loyalty system.
 - Assisted dealers with Loyalty issues, coupon errors on business systems/eCommerce, and loyalty reporting.
 - Solved and troubleshooted issues across multiple technologies and systems (eCommerce, DBS, Loyalty app).
- Coordinated and assisted integrating dealer business systems for embedded customer loyalty.

TECHNOLOGIES and SKILLS

Programming: SQL, Java, Python, R, PHP, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, JSON

Software: Tableau, Tableau Server, Tableau Prep, Alteryx, Snowflake, SQL Server, Visual Studio, Rstudio

CERTIFICATIONS

Tableau Desktop Specialist | Tableau Software | February 2020 **Exam 98-364: Database Fundamentals** | Microsoft | July 2019

EDUCATION

BA, Mathematics

University of Washington

Fall 2011 - Spring 2015

Certificate of Business Intelligence

Bellevue College

Fall 2018 - Spring 2020